

Boris Shminke

Machine Learning Researcher/Engineer



16 June 1986



Nice, France

+33 788769442



https://boris.shminke.ml



boris@shminke.ml

About me -

I'm an ML and big data professional with 10+ years of experience. I'm currently interested in applications of AI with a focus on reinforcement learning and graph-neural networks. I'm Russian with a French residence and work permit.

Languages -

English - full proficiency French - limited proficiency Russian - native

Technologies

Machine Learning

- · reinforcement learning (Ray)
- deep learning (PyTorch)
- · recommender systems

Data Engineering

- Spark, Kafka, Hadoop, AirFlow
- · Oracle, Teradata, SAS
- pandas

DevOps

- Docker
- CircleCI, AppVeyor
- Google Cloud Platform

Team work: git, Scrum, Kanban Python: numpy, scipy, sklearn, Jupyter Other DBs: PostgreSQL, Vertica, MonqoDB

education

Ph.D. (mathematics) 10.2020-09.2023 Université Côte d'Azur Thesis title: Applications of AI to study of finite algebraic structures and automated theorem proving Master equivalent (recognised by ENIC-NARIC) (applied maths) 09.2003-03.2009 Moscow Aviation Institute (National Research University) Thesis title: Application of critical cases theory to stabilization prob-

lems with incomplete information

experience	
French National Centre for Scientific Research (CNRS) PhD candidate developed a collection of OpenAI Gym environments for provers wrote a Python client to Isabelle proof assistant server automatically solved an open research question in abstract algebra created and taught Master courses on distributed big data and rec- ommender systems	10.2020-09.2023
Largest Russian bank (Sberbank) team lead in the AI R&D unit built a financial news recommender for a mobile app with 40M users created and maintained a recommender systems library hired and supervised a team of ML Researcher Engineers	11.2018-09.2020
Online cinema with 30M users (ivi.ru) big data team lead applied model-based movie recommendations to improve CTR maintained the recommender serving over 1000 requests per sec. hired and supervised a team of ML Engineers	11.2015-10.2018
One of the largest Russian learning platforms (netology.ru) part-time instructor&content creator created and taught a course on recommender systems	12.2017-07.2018
Top-30 Russian bank (TRUST) senior risk analyst core developer at a consumer credit automation project	09.2014-10.2015
Moscow office of an international consulting firm (Business & Decision, now part of Orange Group) senior analyst for a project successfully implemented a cross-sell model data pipeline project supervised a team of Data Engineers	05.2014-09.2014
Top-30 Russian banks (Binbank) senior analyst created BI dashboards for consumer credit scoring	05.2013-05.2014

created BI dashboards for consumer credit scoring

Largest BI and Big Data Solutions provider in Russia (Glowbyte) 11.2010-04.2013 senior data engineer

built a data pipeline for an anti-fraud model supervised a team of Data Engineers

Leading Russian developer of IT solutions for air transport (IATVT) 08.2009-10.2010

financial reports automation

Russian ERP software developer (Comtec) 03.2009-08.2009

programmer

full stack development for financial reporting

certificates

Oracle PL/SQL Developer Certified Associate	2015
SAS Certified Advanced Programmer	2014
Oracle Database SQL Certified Expert	2013
Certificate in Advanced English (Cambridge ESOL)	2012
SAS Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9	2011

additional info

In addition to my daytime job, I've contributed code to Apache Spark and Ray RLlib, among other open-source projects. Apart from coding, I enjoy hiking.